nonprofitquarterly.org 2019-09-13

# Privacy Policy - Non Profit News | Nonprofit Quarterly

The _Nonprofit Quarterly_ ( _NPQ_ ) knows that you care how information about you is used and shared, and we appreciate your trust that we will do so carefully and sensibly. This notice describes our privacy policy. By visiting[www.nonprofitquarterly.org](https://nonprofitquarterly.org/) or [our ordering website](https://online.icnfull.com/npc/?action=SUBSCRIPTION&base_country=US), or though social media correspondence (such as _NPQ_ ‘s [Facebook profile](https://www.facebook.com/TheNonprofitQuarterly/) or [Twitter account](https://www.twitter.com/npquarterly)), you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Notice.

### The Simple Version

We use your contact information for in-house purposes only, and do not share any information about you with third parties. Registration and purchases made through our website also opt you into our e-newsletters, from which you’re able to unsubscribe at any time. We think, though, that you’ll like them quite a bit.

### What Personal Information Does NPQ Gather?

 **Information You Give Us**

We receive and store any information you enter into our website or give us in any other way. This includes subscribing to our magazine or e-Newsletters, purchasing back issues, special reprints, or other products, donating to us, or submitting a form (such as a comment) on our website. We ask for personal information so that we can fulfill your request and return your message. If you choose not to provide any of that information, we may not be able to fulfill your request or complete your order, but you will still be free to browse the other sections of the websites owned and administered by _NPQ_.

From time to time, we will send you e-mail announcements about new features, products, and services from _NPQ_ and selected advertisers and affiliates. The quality news and information on NonprofitQuarterly.org and the print magazine are supported by advertising revenue, and a controlled program of e-mail marketing is an important element of our online publishing business. We limit the amount of advertising you receive. On occasion, we will send subscription solicitations to your e-mail or postal mailbox. Some demographic data, volunteered through our annual surveys, are used statistically to provide our advertisers with an accurate profile of our overall readership. We never make any personal data collected from these surveys available to a third party.

### Social Media & Comments

 _NPQ_ uses social media such as website comments, and networks like Facebook and Twitter, to engage readers in dialogue. As mentioned above, _NPQ_ makes use of data collected via these functions on our website. On other networks, we abide by the terms and conditions of that website/service, and reserve the right to use those networks for marketing purposes. Comments made on NonprofitQuarterly.org and _NPQ_ ‘s Facebook account are reviewed and published at our discretion, and through the use of these functions you accept that _NPQ_ is permitted to edit, moderate, and reuse comments for in-house promotional materials. Promotions and advertising are not permitted in this medium, nor is derogatory or hateful speech.

### Automatic Information

When you visit any of our websites, our servers make a log of basic information corresponding to the sites and pages you have visited. This information is stored primarily to track the effectiveness of our websites and individual sections and pages within them. At this time, our general website does not use cookies (alphanumeric identifiers that can be stored by a visitor’s browser to identify them on a future visit, or during a single visit), but they are used on our ordering website to keep track of the items in your shopping cart.

Non-Personal Information may include the browser name, the type of device and technical information transmitted, language preferences, geographic location, time stamps and visited pages, operating systems and other similar information. We may also collect IP addresses which would be irrevocably anonymized.

### How Secure Is Information about Me?

All computers that receive or store personal information are secured by firewalls and other security measures. Additionally, sensitive data such as credit card numbers are encrypted using SSL and other industry standard measures, to provide an additional level of security.

###  **How Do We Collect Your Information?**

We collect personal data if and when online users provide _NPQ_ with your details when you become a customer and provide us with account data based on purchases. We may also collect personal information given voluntarily when contacting us on our website, submitting writing content, advertising requests, downloading an e-book, and/or while registering for a webinar. When you visit _NPQ_ ’s Website, we may collect information about your visit such as your IP address and the pages you visited and when you subscribe and access our educational content we may collect information on when and how you use those services.

###  **Cookies**

A “cookie” is a small piece of information that a website assigns to your device while you are viewing a website. Cookies are very helpful and can be used for various different purposes, which include allowing you to navigate between pages efficiently, remembering your preferences and making the interaction between you and our services quicker and easier. Cookies are also used to help customize your experience. To learn more information about cookies you can visit <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>.

###  **What Do We Do With the Information We Gather?**

We may use the information that you provide and that we gather for the following purposes:

  *  **To Provide Services To You:** We use your information to fulfill orders for online subscriptions, to enable you to view the content on our website, and to otherwise interact with all of the features and services available on our site. We also may use your non-personal information to send and process connection requests.
  *  **For Customer-Service Purposes:** When we communicate with you, we may do so through the e-mail address that you provide to us, notices to your inbox, and other means available. The types of communications may include reminders to create/update your account on Shopify or WooCommerce to access products you have purchased.
  *  **To Personalize Your Services:  **We may use information provided by the user to further personalize the content and information we may send or display to you via email services, and to otherwise personalize your experiences. We may use your information to notify you about employment opportunities, news, and other opportunities from institutions that may be relevant to your interests.
  *  **For Marketing and Promotional Purposes:** NPQ may use your information, such as your e-mail address, to send you news and newsletters, to provide special offers about products and services, or to otherwise contact you about products or information we think may interest you. We also may use the information that we learn about you to assist us in advertising our services on third-party websites.
  *  **To Improve Our Site and Services:  **To better understand how users access and use our Site and Services, in order to improve our Site and Services and respond to user desires and preferences.

###  **What Types of Communication Will You Receive?**

We publish the Nonprofit Newswire daily. Occasionally we may send announcements about _NPQ_ events or products to the mailing list. We do not rent or sell our e-mail lists, although we may occasionally send an announcement, event, or product offering that we think may be of interest on behalf of a partner.

You have choices about the types of communications that you receive from us and from third parties (such as education institutions, recruiters, and service providers).  They may include the following:

  * Daily Newsletters and Weekend Highlights
  * Personalized Columns from _NPQ_ ’s Editors
  * Marketing Information and Emails
  * Nonprofit Resources
  * Subscription Notices
  * Webinar Promotions
  * Donor Appeals

###  **With Whom We Share Information**

We do not sell, trade, or rent user personal information with any other parties. We may share personal Information with our trusted service providers and sponsors only to the extent required to fulfill purposes outlined above. We will only provide our sponsor with information submitted by our online users via submission forms for accessing exclusive site content such as magazine downloads or webinar, and online users will always have the option to omit sharing this information with sponsors.

Non-personal information may be shared with other third parties, as well as for the purpose of developing or delivering advertising, or for the purpose of improving our web services, conducting data analysis or other business purposes. This information may be combined with information we collect from other sources, to the extent that the information remains anonymous. In addition, we may elect to share your personal information with qualified third-party partners for marketing or other similar purposes but only where you agree to share such information. Such partners will be prohibited from disclosing or using such information except for the limited purposes which the users have consented to.

###  **How We Use Information We Collect**

We may use personal data to provide and improve our Services and to meet any binding contractual or legal obligations. For example, to analyze and improve the website functionality and services, such as technical or security purposes and to improve the customer experience. We may also use personal data to market and sell our services, including to communicate with you about same or similar services that we offer. If we do so, we will provide you with an easy and free way to opt-out of receiving such communications in the future.

###  **Notice to Non-U.S. Users.  **

Nonprofit Quarterly is based in the United States.  Use of your information by NPQ is intended for use only within the U.S. and its territories.  If you use our site and our services, your information will be stored in the United States. We may, however, use third-party service providers that are located outside of the United States. Content and use of that content is intended to conform to United States law and practices. Use outside the United States is at your risk, and you agree to comply with all applicable laws and use or nonuse of content.

###  **Notice to California Users**

California residents may request a list of any personal information provided to third parties in the preceding year for direct-marketing purposes, free of charge. California residents [can contact us](https://nonprofitquarterly.org/customer-support/) and must attest that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for your response.

###  **Third-Party Links  **

Our Site and Services may contain links to third-party sites. Any access to and use of such links to advertisers are not governed by this policy, but instead is governed by the privacy policies of those third-party websites. _NPQ_ is not responsible for the information practices of such third-party sites.

###  **Security**

We use industry standard security tools and measures, as well as internal guidelines and organizational procedures to prevent information misuse and data leakage. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means and procedures to protect the information, which considerably reduce the risks of data misuse, we cannot guarantee that our systems will be absolutely safe. If you become aware of any security vulnerability or potential data breach, please contact us immediately at info@npquarterly.org, and we can take the appropriate measures to address such incident.

### Conditions of Use and Revisions

If you have any concern about privacy at dev-npq-site.pantheonsite.io or any of our websites, please send us a description of your concern to[info@npqmag.org](mailto:info@npqmag.org), and we will try to resolve it. Changing business practices and circumstances may require that we make changes to this privacy policy from time to time. Any changes will be reflected on this website. We reserve the right to change these terms from time to time. All changes are effective immediately, and could apply to all access to and use of the site thereafter. Your continued use of the site following changes will be conclusively deemed as acceptance of any new changes to our terms and conditions. We encourage you to check on this page so you may be aware of any changes, as they are binding on you.

* * *

## Contacting Us

You may [contact](https://nonprofitquarterly.org/customer-support/) us to delete your account or have any questions about the privacy aspects of our Services

Our postal address is:  
Nonprofit Quarterly  
Attn: Website Privacy Request  
112 Water St Ste 400  
Boston, MA 02109

We can be reached via e-mail at [info@npqmag.org](mailto:info@npqmag.org).
